Kevin Craig

Mississauga ON linkedin.com/in/kevinmmcraig kevinmmcraig@gmail.com kevinmmcraig.ca (416) 577-2720

I will bring a fresh, positive outlook to the workplace, strive to work hard and never give up. I will utilize my knowledge and expertise to create and maintain beautiful, efficient code.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Proficient with C++, MySQL, scripting and web-oriented programming languages, including: Perl, Python, HTML5/CSS, JavaScript, and PHP
- Thorough knowledge of Linux and Windows desktop and server operating systems
- Courses taken during school include: PC Hardware & Software, Linux and Windows Administration, Web
 page Development, Data Communications, Scripting, OS Fundamentals, Databases, and Programming

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Strong communication, analytical, and problem solving skills
- Confident personality, motivated, with an honest, patient, and positive attitude
- Very quick learner, organized and accurate, with a desire to continuously learn
- Adept at multitasking and managing time effectively in any fast-paced environment

EDUCATION

Computer Networking and Technical Support Diploma

Class of 2016

St. Lawrence College, Kingston ON

GPA of 3.8

• Learned the inner workings of computer networks and how to make servers run faster and more securely

Bachelor of Science in Physics

Class of 2014

McMaster University, Hamilton ON

Gained experience in C++, FORTRAN and LaTeX programming languages

WORK EXPERIENCE

Computer Bench Technician

January 2016 - April 2016

ResponseIT, Kingston ON

- Troubleshot hardware and software of various types of desktop, server, and laptop computers
- Created a server capable of installing different versions of the Windows operating system remotely
- Went on several service calls to diagnose and fix urgent technical issues that clients were having
- Exposed to other areas of technology including IP phone systems, virtualization (mainly with vSphere), remote accessing, hard drive cloning software, and determining evidence of water damage to electronics
- Learned the business aspect to the information technology field

Kevin Craig

kevinmmcraig@gmail.com kevinmmcraig.ca (416) 577-2720

Industrial Cleaning Technician

Summers 2015, 2016

Pressure Kleen Services, Etobicoke ON

- Cleaned kitchen exhaust and garbage disposal systems, underground parking lots, and City of Toronto park facilities using pressure washing equipment
- Met with clients to specify scope of work, cleaned as much as possible in a time-constrained setting
- Organized the logistics of transporting equipment to the site, often driving through busy streets
- Always followed proper safety protocols to ensure the safety of myself and those around me

Math Tutor

September 2014 – December 2014

St. Lawrence College, Kingston ON

- Organized the meeting time and place, ensuring a quiet and comfortable learning environment
- Articulated clear explanations for the material covered
- Made sure student's questions were always fully answered
- Assured student was maintaining a balanced understanding of the material

Amusement Device Mechanic

Summer 2013

Checkers Fun Factory, Hamilton ON

- With the help of one or two others, loaded company trucks with equipment to bring to site
- Assembled and dismantled bouncy castles and other carnival equipment within requested time period
- Ensured bouncy castles where securely in place with large metal stakes
- Supervised children, always enforcing the acceptable safety limit according to specified guidelines

Research Student Summer 2012

Xerox Research Centre of Canada, Mississauga ON

- Designed a computer program to control the automation of delivering a developer and toner mixture to the housing apparatus of a photocopier
- Interfaced the apparatus to a controller that inputted values to the LABVIEW programming environment
- Calculated useful percentages to test and improve certain properties of toner
- Worked independently and under pressure

Factory Worker Summer 2011

Fourmark, Oakville ON

- Packaged plastic containers into boxes from an assembly line
- Always punctual and put safety first

Sobeys, Mississauga ON

Cashier

September 2008 – November 2010

- Handled cash, and was very friendly and helpful
- Often in charge of the customer service desk

References Available Upon Request